about

Product Engineer and Ex.Data Scientist with 2+ years of experience in Designing ML Models, ETL pipelines and Analysis. Possess PGD in Big Data Analytics from CDAC ACTS (HQ), Pune. Seeking to leverage my Mathematical knowledge, Analytics abilities, and ML models development competency in the role of Data Analytics.

EDUCATION

CDAC -PGD Big Data Analytics
Pune
Maharashtra
2018 – 2019

B.Tech. ECE Rajasthan Technical University Jaipur, RJ 2010 – 2014

SKILLS

Machine Learning
Reinforcement Learning, GAN
Python, Java, R
Big Data, Spark, Hive, Kafka
SQL (DBMS)
Mathematics (Statistics, Calculus)
Pytorch, TensorFlow

contact



(+91) 8239-3838-47



rsohlot@gmail.com



Rewari, Haryana, IN



Linkedin.com/in/rsohlot rsohlot.github.io

CERTIFICATION

Market Analysis Course (Jan 2017 – March 2017)

Machine Learning, Coursera (May 2016- June 2017)

Spark Working (Dec 2019 – Dec 2019)

GAN with Pytorch (May 2020 – June 2020)

Al Workflow: Feature Engineering and Bias Detection (July 2020 – July 2020)

professional experience

2020 - Present

Product Engineer, Infinx HealthCare, Bangalore

- IRIS: An embedded quick sight dashboard to help client analysis the revenue. Build a generalized ETL pipeline to make it easier to onboard newer client.
- IROS: A product to prioritized insurance charges to work on to get maximum revenue.
- Handling 60 Lakh record transformation per batch. (EMR + pyspark)
- Tools used: Redshift, glue, s3, EC2, EMR, pyspark, Athena.

2019 - 2020

Associate Data Scientist, KratinLLC, Nagpur

- Designed a Time Series Model give accuracy up to 97% used to create an AI smart SAP tool to maximize the workforce utilization considering all the preferences and requirements. Results in saving the 500 miles every week of the workforce traveling.
- Estimated the future demand to get the best assignment of workforce. Tools used prophet, optaplanner, Django, plotly, pandas, docker.
- Designed and implemented the warehouse for the BI and analytics. Saved daily 1 hr. task of the team to fetch, validate and store the data. This was done with Hadoop, hive, spark, hue, Apache Atlus, Apache ranger.

2016 - 2018

Co-Founder, WHT, Bhiwadi, RJ

 Founded WHT. It was a Logistics Firm.Learnt the Logistics business flow of Northern India. Firm manages complete workflow of goods for the various Industries.